RG 004:120, Roxbury Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Roxbury Probate Court records
1842-1992, bulk 1842-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Roxbury District)
12 cubic feet
Record books, 1842-1952; Probate files, 1842-1992, bulk 1842-1976.
RG004_120
1930-003, 2011-045, 2011-046
Historical Note
Roxbury, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1796, Parent Town: Woodbury
The Roxbury Probate District was constituted June 6, 1842, from the Woodbury Probate District. The Roxbury Probate District merged with the Oxford, Southbury, Washington, and Woodbury Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region # 22 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethlehem, Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, Washington, Watertown, and Woodbury.
Town of Roxbury, Probate District chronology:
October 1796 - June 5, 1842, Woodbury District
June 6, 1842 - January 4, 2011, Roxbury District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 22 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-12, 1842-1952. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 18. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1842-1992, bulk 1842-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1842-1921 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 1 to 12. There are two volumes numbered 11.
Probate files in accessions 1930-003 and 2011-046 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1930-003 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-046.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Roxbury
Places:
Roxbury (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-045, Record books, 1842-19452; and Accession 2011-046, Probate files, 1870-1992, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 7, 9-10, 1842-1927; probate files, 1842-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1930-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): April 7, 1930 (1842-1921).
The record books in accession 2011-045 and the probate files in accession 2011-046 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 12, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1842-1952; 6 cubic feet (13 volumes); 2011-045
  - Records, 1842-1859 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1858-1876 (Volume 2)
  - Orders and decrees, 1867-1897 (Volume 3)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1874-1889 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1890-1898 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1898-1919 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1897-1901 (Volume 7)
  - Bonds, 1896-1952 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1901-1910 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1905-1927 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1920-1935 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1923-1927 (Volume 11)
    On spine: "Miscellaneous"
  - Orders and decrees, 1938-1945 (Volume 12)
- Probate files, 1842-1921; 4 cubic feet; 1930-003
  - Addis - Beers, H. (Drawer 1)
  - Beers, I. - Bronson (Drawer 2)
  - Brown - Davidson (Drawer 3)
  - Delaney - Garrison (Drawer 4)
  - Garrity - Hurd (Drawer 5)
  - Hurlburt - Lewis, C. (Drawer 6)
  - Lewis, D. - Northrop (Drawer 7)
  - Odell - Ryan (Drawer 8)
  - Sanford - Spalding (Drawer 9)
  - Squire - Trowbridge (Drawer 10)
  - Tuttle - Weller (Drawer 11)
  - Wells - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 12)
- Inventory Control Book, 1842-1921; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1930-003
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1870-1992, bulk 1905-1976; 2 cubic feet; 2011-046
  - A - G (Box 1)
  - H - Y (Box 2)